Welcome to the Marvin home page!
The ‘Help’ button towards the middle of the screen is a link to the Marvin documentation, including tutorials. We recommend going through the documentation after this exercise.
At the top of the page are links to ‘Known Issues’ and ‘What’s New’. The link at the very left labeled ‘Marvin’ will take you back to this Marvin home page.
To look up a galaxy, you need its plate and ifu design or MaNGA ID number.
In the box that says ‘Plate or ID Designation’, type ‘7443’ and hit return.
Then you will see some information about this plate and below a set of images for all the IFUs of galaxies observed with this plate. You can then click on the image for ‘12703’.
On the galaxy page there is a lot of information!
In the top left there is some basic information. There are also a few links to download the data for this galaxy and also how to use python to import the galaxy in Marvin tools.
Click on the red box that says ‘Map/SpecView Off’ (it should turn green and now say ‘Map/SpecView On’).
Scroll down to see an image of the galaxy (left) and a spectrum of a spaxel (right). When you hover the mouse over the galaxy image you should see a blue dot.
The right panel shows by default the spectrum in the central spaxel.
If you click on different locations for different spaxels, the spectrum on the right will change to reflect the spectrum at that spaxel.
You can also zoom in on different part of the spectrum by clicking and dragging the mouse across the section of interest. You can zoom in both horizontally and vertically.
With the spectrum on the right you can hover the mouse along the spectrum and the value of the flux at that wavelength shows up in the top right corner of the plot.
To un-zoom and get back to the full spectrum, double click on the plot.
Now scroll down the the DAP Maps, where you should see an example of three commonly used maps.
As in the image panel, you can click on different areas in the maps to see the spectrum in that spaxel.
Note that the wavelength is in the observed frame and not the rest frame.
Under the tab that says ‘3 items selected’, you can click on this and change which maps are shown.
The description of the different quantities shown in the maps is given in the data model.
A selected map with have a green check mark next to it. You can select any number of maps.
Once you have selected which maps you would like, click on the yellow ‘Get Maps’ button to generate the desired maps.
Depending on your Internet connection this could take a while.
You can also change the binning scheme by clicking on the next tab to the right.
If you want to reset your selections, click on the ‘Reset Maps’ blue button.
The green button labeled ‘Use Maps in Python’, shows you the python script for creating the maps using the Marvin tools.
We recommend you to try the Marvin tools, which offer further options to interact with maps.
Now we will check out the galaxy properties. To do so click on ‘Galaxy Properties’.
In this section, you can plot different galaxy properties for all the currently observed MaNGA galaxies, with your current galaxy in red for comparison.
To zoom in, you can click and drag the mouse over a section you want zoomed in.
To un-zoom, click on the ‘Reset zoom’ button.
You can also change which parameters are being plotted.
There is a table on the left with the various NSA parameters listed.
Only the parameters in bold (12) can be used for the plots.
Click on the parameter of choice and drag the name over to plot and axis of choice.
You should get a grabbing hand symbol as you click and drag.
In addition to the scatter plots, you can also see 12 of the NSA parameters as box and whisker plots.
Click on the ‘Box and Whisker’ link to see a set of these plots, and horizontally scroll to see all the plots.
The boxes span the first to third quartile (25 to 75%) with the middle horizontal line being the median.
The dashed lines span from 10 to 90%. If you hover over the red dot, you can see its value, as well as the outliers in gray circles
For more features and descriptions of Marvin web, see Marvin Docs!!